Alchemy, the science of understanding,
deconstructing, and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create
something out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be given.
This is the law of equivalent exchange,
the basis of all alchemy.
In accordance with this law,
there is a taboo among alchemists.
Human transmutation is strictly forbidden.
For what could equal the value
of a human soul?
Kono omoi wo keshite shimau niwa
mada jinsei nagai dsho?
Yarinokoshite'ru koto
yarinaoshite mitai kara
Yume no tsuzuki oikakete ita hazu na no ni
Magarikunetta
hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
Ano koro mitai ni tte modoritai wake ja nai ni
Nakushite kita sora wo sagashite'ru
Wakatte kuremasu you ni
Gisei ni natta you na
kanashii kao wa yamete yo
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
Zutto kurushiku seotte'ku n da
Deguchi mienai kanjou meiro ni
dare wo matte'ru no?
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta you ni
motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
Nani kar nogaretai n da
genjitsu tte yatsu?
Kanaeru tame ni ikite'ru n datte
Sakebitaku naru yo Kikoete imasu ka?
Bunai n nante yatte'rarenai kara
...kaeru basho mo nai no
Yasashisa niwa itsumo kansha shite'ru
Dakara tsuyoku naritai
(I'm on the way)
Natsukashiku naru
konna itami mo kangei jan
The town of Liore had fallen under
the control of Father Cornello,
A corrupt priest who used alchemy combined
with a Philosopher's Stone to deceive his people.
Ed and Al came to Liore and put
a stop to the priest's sinister plans.
The Philosopher's Stone, however,
was revealed to be a fake.
Their leader exposed as a fraud,
the hopes of the citizens of Liore were crushed.
"Stand up and walk. Move forward."
These were Ed's words to Rose, words
he had once needed to hear himself.
You are Basque Grand,
the Iron Blood Alchemist, correct?
Why? Who's asking?
Foolish alchemists who have
turned their backs on the ways of God...
Shall all be punished.
I see. You must be the bloodthirsty murderer who's been
making a habit of targeting State Alchemists, lately.
Well, this time,
you picked the wrong target!
You're fast...
Try this!
A little more?!
Hmph.
That wasn't so difficult.
What?
No! How?!
Now you perish.
HUGHES: Another State Alchemist dead.
ARMSTRONG: This killer is highly skilled.
For all we know, you could
be the next one he comes after.
HUGHES: Major, you watch yourself.
Understood.
[CAR APPROACHING]
Fuhrer Bradley, Your Excellency.
What brings you here?
BRADLEY: I got word of what happened.
Lt. Colonel Hughes, you're
the officer in charge of this case?
Yes, sir.
Should you need any
additional personnel, just ask.
The man doing this is a traitor.
I want him stopped.
Sir.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Lieutenant Breda.
Right.
Jeez. The Colonel's sure letting
his work pile up again, huh?
Havoc, give me a hand, will ya?
I've got plenty to do over here already.
Next up...
Who's this?
FALMAN:
Lieutenant Yoki.
Remember? The crook who was using the Youswell
coal mine concessions to line his own pockets?
Anyway, the Elric brothers exposed what that
dirty thief was up to and now he's on the run.
[RADIO STATIC]
Master Sergeant Fuery,
how's the radio?
The receiver on this thing's seen better days.
I think I'm gonna have to replace it.
Huh?
Hey, it's Edward and Alphonse!
HAWKEYE: Welcome back, boys.
Go on in.
The Colonel's expecting you.
Well done on the Lior case,
you two. Nice work.
I appreciate you
resolving the matter.
No big deal.
It's not like we did it for you.
Right. The Philosopher's Stone.
Another false lead?
Yeah, after all that,
the Stone was a fake.
Even so, the power it gave Cornello
was real enough.
He transmuted this huge
Chimera right in front of us.
I still wonder how he was
able to use the Stone to do that.
I'm not familiar enough with the field of
bioalchemy to really understand it.
Yeah, I'm kinda curious about that, too.
It might be worth looking into.
Who knows? Maybe we'll find something
that could help us restore our bodies.
AL: Mmm!
It might help if you
consulted a specialist.
BOTH: Huh?
The Sewing Life Alchemist, Shou Tucker.
He's done some heavy research into
Chimera transmutation. I'll introduce you.
You would do that for us?!
Okay, what's the catch?
You want something, don't you?
Don't doubt my motives. I'm trying to
repay you for your work on the Lior case!
Doing you a favor is better
than being indebted to you.
MUSTANG: Two years ago, Tucker transmuted a
Chimera that could understand human speech.
That earned him his
certification as a State Alchemist.
By understand human speech.
You mean...
Wait, you mean it talks?!
A Chimera?
Right.
Supposedly...
It only said one thing.
"I want to die."
After that, it refused to eat
until it got its wish.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
ED: Man, this house is huge.
Huh?
[HOWLING]
[ED YELPING]
You okay, Ed?!
Daddy!
Huh?
There are people out here. Look!
Nina, this is why I told
you to keep the dog tied up.
I'm sorry about the mess.
Ever since my wife ran out,
this place has been a wreck.
I'm not much of a housekeeper.
[SIGHS]
Now that we're all settled in, let me
say that it's a pleasure to meet you, Edward.
As the Colonel told you, I'm the
Sewing Life Alchemist, Shou Tucker.
Ed is interested in the
field of biologic alchemy.
He would like to have a look at
your research, if that's possible.
Oh, yes, certainly.
I don't mind.
However...
If you want me to show you
the tricks I've got up my sleeve,
it's only fair you show me the
tricks you've got up yours as well.
It's the code we live by,
equivalent exchange.
Now, why are you interested
in bioalchemy?
Oh, um, Ed...
Well, you see, he's...
Colonel.
You transmuted your mother?
As an eleven-year-old child?
I see.
So that's what earned you the title
"Fullmetal Alchemist."
You've had a rough time of it
for someone so young.
[SIGHS]
I can't say for sure if it's going
to be of any use to you or not...
But why don't you go ahead
and take a look at my laboratory?
[VARIOUS ANIMALS SNARLING, GROWLING,
SCREECHING AND SQUAWKING]
AL: Oh...!
TUCKER: It's kind of embarrassing.
I'm fairly widely regarded
as an authority on Chimeras...
But the truth is, it hasn't actually
been going that well lately.
ED: Oh... amazing!
TUCKER: This is my library.
Feel free to look around.
All right, let's dive in!
I'll start with this shelf.
I'll try starting over here!
I'm going to head back to work now.
I'll send somebody by
to get you this evening.
They've got some ability to focus.
I'm not sure they even
know we're here anymore.
Quite a catch, these two.
A couple of prodigies.
[CLOCK TICKING]
Hmm?
[NINA GASPS]
[GIGGLE]
[NINA GIGGLING]
Woo- hoo! Way up high!
[AL AND NINA GIGGLING]
Al! What are you doing?
You're supposed to be reading!
Uh...Nina looked like she
wanted to play!
Well, in case you forgot, we
didn't come here to play horsey!
Huh?
[DOG HOWLS]
[ED YELPING]
Alexander says that he
wants to play too!
That's what you want, is it?
You've bested me twice, dog...
But playtime is over.
I will not lose this time!
I, Edward Elric, will use my considerable
powers to vanquish you!
You mangy mutt!
[GIGGLING]
Hey, Chief!
Your ride has arrived.
What are you up to
down there, Ed?
Oh, uh...let's just say I'm taking a
break from a long day of research.
After all that,
you must be dog tired.
[LAUGHING]
Why don't you come
on back tomorrow?
[GASPS]
You're really going to come again?!
We'll play some more tomorrow!
Okay, Nina?
'Kay!
Oh, Mr. Tucker, I almost forgot.
I've got a message for you.
It's from the Colonel. He says,"Don't forget,
Assessment day is coming soon."
Yes. Please assure him I know.
Right.
Hey, Daddy?
What does
"Assessment Day" mean?
State Alchemists have to report on their research
once a year in order to keep their certification.
You see, last year, Nina, your
daddy didn't get a very good evaluation.
Unless I do something really impressive this year,
I won't be a State Alchemist anymore.
Huh? No, you'll
do just fine, Daddy!
I know you will,
you're always studying so much!
[CHUCKLES]
You're right, Nina. I have to try hard.
Or we'll be left with nothing...
Again.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
AL: Your mother
left two years ago?
Daddy said she went back
to live at her parents' house.
It must get kind of lonely with just you
and your dad living in this big house, huh?
Mm-mm. Not really.
Daddy's so nice, and plus
I've got Alexander to play with, too!
But lately, Daddy's been
studying in his lab all the time...
I guess that does
make me a little bit lonely.
[YAWNING]
My shoulders are killing me.
Maybe you should try to
move around some, brother.
Yeah, not a bad idea, Al.
Hey, you mangy mutt!
[BARKS]
Looks like you could
use some exercise.
[AL GIGGLES]
Let's go, too, Nina!
[GIGGLE]
[ED YELLING PLAYFULLY]
C'mon, c'mon!
ED: C'mon, you can't catch me!
NINA: Wait up!
C'mon, slowpokes!
Ha-ha!
I'm gonna get you!
Look out! Here I come!
[AL AND NINA GIGGLING]
ED: [MUFFLED GRUNT]
AL: Huh?
[GIGGLING]
[SOUNDS OF PLAYING
CONTINUE IN THE DISTANCE]
"Don't forget, Assessment Day
is coming soon."
HUGHES: What I wanna know is why this guy is only
targeting State Alchemists and no one else.
If it's the military he's trying to hurt,
he could go after normal soldiers.
Surely soldiers would be easier
to kill than highly skilled Alchemists...
especially ones that
have been State-certified.
Maybe the certification
is the reason.
Hmm?
State Alchemists are given
high pay and special privilege.
There must be any number of people
who envy them for their positions.
Or perhaps they feel they have not upheld
their creed, "Alchemist be thou for the people."
Alchemists who are supposed to be pillars of science and truth are
turned into the military's walking weapons as soon as they receive certification.
There are plenty of people, I'm sure...
Who have not forgotten the role that
State Alchemists played in the Ishvalan Civil War
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
I have a report, sir.
A canvas has revealed that yesterday,
at 9.30, or right around that time,
a man with a large scar on his face was sighted in the
Central City train station by multiple station employees.
The station?!
Looks like that bastard got away.
Before I earned my State Alchemist
certification, our life was terrible.
We were so poor in those days.
My wife couldn't stand living that
kind of life, so she left us.
I can't afford to
fail this assessment.
I don't wanna go back to those days again.
I don't even think I could.
Don't worry, Daddy,
it's okay!
If those people do tell you no, me and
Alexander will growl at them until they say yes!
[AL GIGGLING]
You tell 'em, Nina!
Hey, Nina. I've got an idea.
Do you want to play with Daddy tomorrow?
Really?!
Yeah.
Woo-hoo!
Alexander! Daddy says he's
going to play with us tomorrow!
[ALEXANDER BARKS]
[ED AND AL CHUCKLING]
[DOORBELL RINGING]
Hello, Mr. Tucker!
Thanks for having us again today!
Huh?
Mr. Tucker?
Hey! Nina?!
[DOOR OPENS]
AL: Mr. Tucker!
ED: There you are!
So you are home.
Yes.
I did it, boys.
I finally did it.
A Chimera that
understands human speech.
Here, let me show you.
Listen to me.
That person over there, that's Edward.
That person... Edward...
Yes, that's very good. Well done!
That's amazing!
It can actually talk!
Now I don't have to worry
about losing my certification!
That person Ed...ward...
Woah...
Big brother, Ed...
[GASP]
ED: Mr. Tucker, when did you
first get your state certification?
Let's see...
It was two years ago.
And when did your wife leave you?
That was two years ago, too.
I just have one more
question for you.
Nina and Alexander... Where are they?!
[GASP]
Damn brat, figuring it out so quickly.
Brother!
Oh yeah, I figured it out!
You did it again!
Two years ago, it was your wife,
This time, you used your own daughter
and her dog to transmute a talking Chimera!
You can only do so much
with animals, after all.
It's much easier when you start
with a human, isn't that right?
I don't see what you're so upset about.
This is how we progress.
Human experimentation
is a necessary step.
I would think a scientist
should understand—
ED: Shut up! Do you really think
you can get away with this?!
Messing around with someone's
life like that... Your own daughter!
Someone's life, you say?
[LAUGHS] You'd know all about that,
wouldn't you?
Look at you, Fullmetal Alchemist,
look at your legs...
Your arm...
Your brother...
Those things are also the result of messing
around with somebody's life, aren't they?
Shut up!
[CACKLES] We are the same!
We're the same! You're just like me!
We're not!
Oh, but yes we are! The opportunity
was right in front of us and we took it!
We had to, even though we
knew it was against the rules!
No!
Not me!
Alchemists don't...
Do that!
I'm not... I'm not!
Brother!
If you keep this up,
he'll die!
Edward, no...
Daddy...
Do you... hurt... Daddy?
I'm sorry. Even with all our power,
we can't do anything to change you back.
I'm sorry....
I'm sorry.
Can we play...now?
Can we play now?
I made it just in time.
I get to remain a
State Alchemist...I passed!
[PATHETIC WHIMPERING]
Like hell you're staying a State Alchemist...
Like hell.
Can we... play now?
[PAINED YELLING]
Damn it!
HAWKEYE: If there was an example
of the devil's work in this world...
this world, this case would
definitely be it.
MUSTANG: The devil, huh?
A State Alchemist must
be willing to act,
Able to take another's life
when ordered to, without questioning.
In some ways, Mr. Tucker's actions
and our own may not be all that far apart.
When it comes to interfering
with other people's lives...
We choose our own path,
knowing full well what we're doing.
That's the way it is.
Right, Fullmetal?
You will more than likely come
across cases like this again in the future.
And you may end up having to
get your own hands dirty, as well.
You gonna shut down
like this every time?
We may be called dogs
of the military...
We may even be
cursed as devils.
It doesn't matter.
Al and I are still going to
get our bodies back.
We know the truth.
We know we're not devils.
We know we're not gods.
We're human.
We're only human!
We can't even do anything
to save one innocent little girl.
So what good are we, then?
I wonder why no one's
capable of understanding me.
Nina...
[THUNDER CRACKS]
You're Shou Tucker, correct?
Who are you? Not military.
Who are you?!
How did you get in here?
There were military police out front!
Foolish alchemists who turn
their backs on the ways of God...
...shall be punished.
Daddy's hurting...
Daddy hurts...
No, daddy...
You poor creature.
Once you have been given this form,
there is no way of separating you again.
At least your passing will be in peace.
[THUNDER CRACKS]
God,
Hear me.
Two human souls have
just been returned to you.
Please accept them
into your loving arms.
Please grant these poor lost souls
everlasting peace and salvation.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee kimi wa oboete imasu ka
Yakusoku chigiri shoka
no kaze ga tsutsumu
futari yorisotta
Muri na egao no ura
nobita kage o kakumau
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei o erabu
Table no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
kuuhaku no yoru o kuru hazu no nai asa mo
zenbu wakatte'tan da
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
Hatasenakatta yakusoku o idaite
futari arukidasu
The rain pours down in East City.
Still grief-stricken over the death of Nina,
Ed and Al are attacked by the mysterious man, Scar.
In a moment of crisis, Ed must make a desperate decision
while the life of his brother hangs in the balance.
Next time on
Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 5, Rain of Sorrows
What will Edward decide?
And will he be able to
live with the consequences?